# **Andrew O'Connell**

721 W Buckingham Pl. Chicago, IL 60657 | (630) 917-9099

aoconnell099@gmail.com | https://aoconnell099.github.io/andrew-oconnell/

Expected: Dec. 2021

## **SUMMARY**

Bachelor of Science candidate in Computer Science. Have worked in a team to conduct extended research and present findings at an academic symposium. Passionate about learning new technologies and constantly looks for implementation methods to increase efficiency.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Illinois at Chicago (UIC)

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 3.00/4.00

**SKILLS** 

**Languages**: C++, Java, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Python, PHP **Frameworks**: React, React Native, Selenium, Phaser, BabylonJS

**Software**: Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook **Databases**: Firebase, IndexedDB, Microsoft Access

## **PROJECTS**

• Job searching mobile app published on Expo

- Fully functioning retro arcade gaming machine and media player using a Raspberry Pi 3
- Created and manage website and ad campaign for AI Waterworks Inc.
- Two dimensional web arcade game
- Online multiplayer rock, paper, scissors, lizard, spock game
- Three dimensional puzzle game
- CTA train tracker clone app

## **LEADERSHIP**

Member of the Chicago Engineering Design Team at UIC.

Spring 2017 - Fall 2018

- Attended meetings
- Assisted in battlebot structural and software conceptual design
- Volunteered as a counselor at the Muscular Dystrophy Association's Summer Camp; promoted to cabin leader in 2014 and 2015.

Summer 2010 - 2015

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Chicago Electrical Trauma Rehabilitation Institute - Chicago, IL

Web Developer

December 2019 – Present

Update all company websites to comply with current SEO standards and make any design changes that are desired.

#### Jefferson Tap & Grille - Chicago, IL

Barback

July 2018 – September 2019

Maintained the area surrounding the bar. Stocked the bar on an ongoing basis while serving food and drinks, receiving orders, and cleaning tables. Worked in a group to ensure a seamless service for large parties for up to 150 people.

John O'Connell Plumbing - Glen Ellyn, IL

Assistant Plumber

June 2009 - Aug. 2013;

May 2015 - May 2018

Measured, cleaned, cut, and joined copper, PVC, and gas piping to fit the specified requirements for the job. Interacted with the customer and explained any technicalities they were confused about.

Received calls and scheduled new jobs based on our current calendar.